Inventory of the Harry Roscoe Snyder papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Harry Roscoe Snyder papers
1927-1998
97022
Hoover Institution Archives
36 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes (15.7 linear feet)
Datebooks, correspondence, speeches and writings, notes, memoranda, reports, studies, printed matter, maps, posters, and photographs relating to Arabian American Oil Company personnel training and education in Saudi Arabia, American educational assistance in the Middle East, the promotion of Arab-American cultural ties, and the establishment of American military installations in Saudi Arabia during and immediately after World War II.
Snyder, Harry Roscoe, 1906-1988
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1997.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
Arthur A. Cervi miscellany, Hoover Institution Archives
J.C. Hurewitz collection, Hoover Institution Archives
Philip C. McConnell papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Harley C. Stevens papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
1906 January 18 Born, Chicago, Illinois
1925-1927 Minister, First Methodist Church, Bear Creek, Wisconsin
1927 B.A., economics and geology, Lawrence University, Wisconsin
1927-1929 Adjunct professor of commerce, American University of Beirut
1930-1942 Assistant manager and editor, McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc., San Francisco and New York
1939-1942 M.A., geography, Teacher's College, Columbia University
1942-1946 Military service (Intelligence Officer, Section Chief, Persian Gulf Area, Islamic Specialist; Military Intelligence Service, War Department, General Staff)
1942 Lecturer on Iran, School of Military Government, University of Virginia
1945 Negotiated an agreement with King 'Abd al-'Aziz Ibn Saud for U.S. airfield in the Eastern Province of Saudi Arabia
1946-1947 Associate director, Near East College Association, New York
1947-1949 U.S. Air Force, Chief, Saudi Arabian Training Mission and Commanding Officer, 1414th Training Squadron (Dhahran)
1949-1952 Director of education and Arab training, Arabian American Oil Company (Aramco)
1952-1955 Coordinator of general and industrial education, Aramco
1955-1956 Leave of absence to pursue EdD at Teacher's College, Columbia University
1956 Acting coordinator, general and industrial education, Aramco
1956-1957 Education liaison for Saudi Arabian government, Aramco
1957-1965 Coordinator, Saudi Arabian government/Aramco Education Services
1963 Ed.D., college administration and educational foundations, Columbia University Author, Community College Education for Saudi Arabia, Ann Arbor, Michigan, University Microfilms, Inc. (Ed.D. dissertation)
1965-1972 Professional consultant service of the Saudi Arabian government to the College of Petroleum and Minerals, Aramco
1972 Educational consultant and lecturer on Middle Eastern affairs
1988 April 6 Died, Tucson, Arizona
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers of Harry Roscoe Snyder, consisting of datebooks, correspondence, speeches and writings, notes, memoranda, reports, charts, clippings, printed matter, maps, posters, and photographs, relate to Arabian American Oil Company personnel training and education in Saudi Arabia, American educational assistance in the Middle East, promotion of Arab-American cultural ties, and the establishment of American military installations in Saudi Arabia during and immediately after World War II.
The papers reflect Snyder's lifetime of engagements in Middle Eastern, particularly Saudi Arabian, affairs and education. The correspondence and printed matter of the American Friends of the Arabs ( Career File), a short-lived organization started by Snyder and Elihu Grant, attempts to open up conversations among academics and journalists regarding Palestine and Zionism in the U.S. and abroad.
While serving in the military, Snyder helped negotiate an agreement for a U.S. airfield in Dhahran for use during World War II. Because the agreement was not settled until after the war's end and with a brand new airfield built, Snyder was chosen to command the United States Air Force 1414th Training Division in their Saudi Arabian Training Mission. This portion of the Career File consists of materials from the development and implementation of this training program, including correspondence, memoranda, and photographs.
To meet the demands of oil production, the Arabian American Oil Company (Aramco) developed industrial training centers in Abqaiq, Dhahran, and Ras Tanura. Snyder's role as education coordinator in the Training Department of Aramco required him to deliver training and educational services to maintain these centers and encourage the growth of skilled trade workers in Saudi Arabia.
Among the materials relating to industrial training in the Aramco Education and Arab Training File are records of the company's efforts to build elementary and secondary schools in the Eastern province of Saudi Arabia. Reports to the Saudi Arabian government on the state of operations in the company, correspondence and memoranda regarding projects, and charts relating to enrollment and curriculum development of company-built/Saudi Arabian government schools are among the highlights of these records. Other materials relating to education in Saudi Arabia, including schools for girls, can also be found in the Subject File.
As a result of his work as a consultant for architecture firms in the United States and Saudi Arabia ( Educational Consulting File), Snyder's papers include materials relating to the development, construction, and operation of several academic institutions in Saudi Arabia. Although not all of these projects materialized, the records in this series add to the understanding of educational developments within the kingdom. In addition, the series includes materials from the development of a Saudi Arabian airline cadet program, directed by Hamzah Dabbagh in consultation with Snyder.
The Datebooks include diary entries, notes, contacts, and schedules. There is a single book for each date, with the exception of 1968 and 1971, which each have two.
Arabian American Oil Company.; United States. Air Force.; Arab countries--Relations--United States.; Education--Middle East.; Education--Saudi Arabia.; Petroleum industry and trade--Saudi Arabia.; Saudi Arabia--Military relations--United States.; United States--Military relations--Saudi Arabia.; United States--Relations--Saudi Arab countries.; World War, 1939-1945--Saudi Arabia.
- Biographical File, 1927-1987 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Consists of clippings, curriculum vita, identification cards, correspondence, and programs, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Clippings, 1927-1980 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Curriculum vita, 1968-1987 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Family papers, 1957-1966 (Folder 1: 3-4)
    - Biography of Olive Snyder, 1957 (Folder 1: 3)
    - Essay about history of women in Middle East by Olive Snyder, 1966 (Folder 1: 4)
  - Identification cards and permits from military service, 1942-1961 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Interview, 1982 (Folder 1: 6)
  - Letters to friends and family, 1928-1929 (Folder 1: 7)
  - Minutes and constitution of All-College Club at Lawrence College, 1927 (Folder 1: 8)
  - Programs from graduation commencement ceremony, 1942 (Folder 1: 9)
  - Salary record from Aramco (1949-1965), 1966 (Folder 1: 10)
- Datebooks, 1947-1983 (Boxes 1-6)
  Includes 38 datebooks arranged in two groups, datebooks and inserts, then chronologically.
  - 1947-1952 (Box 1)
  - 1953-1960 (Box 2)
  - 1961-1968 (Box 3)
  - 1968-1971 (Box 4)
  - 1972 (Box 5)
  - 1974-1981 (Box 5)
  - 1982-1983 (Box 6)
  - Inserts, 1948-1983 (Box 6)
    Includes loose papers, photographs, and other ephemera that were folded and inserted into datebooks.
    - 1948-1966 (Folder 6: 1-19)
    - 1976 (Folder 6: 20)
    - 1978 (Folder 6: 21)
    - 1980-1981 (Folder 6: 22-23)
    - 1983 (Folder 6: 24)
      Includes 3 slides from 1944.
- Speeches and Writings, 1946-1986 (Boxes 6-7)
  Consists of articles, essays, speeches, commencement addresses, and sermons, arranged chronologically.
  - "Will the Middle East Struggle Between Russia and Britain Mean War?,", 1946 March 26 (Folder 6: 25)
  - "The Jewish Problem,", 1946-1986 (Folder 6: 26-31)
    Includes drafts and revisions.
  - Portion of speech given at American University of Beirut (Folder 6: 32)
  - "The Story of Americans in the Middle East,", 1950 May 20 (Folder 7: 1)
  - "Headquarters Education and Arab Training,", 1950 November (Folder 7: 2)
  - "How Odd of God to Choose the Jews,", 1952 April 5 (Folder 7: 3)
    Draft.
  - "The Art of Teaching,", 1953 November 19 (Folder 7: 4)
  - "Why Are We Here?,", 1954 May 27 (Folder 7: 5)
    Includes drafts titled "Bread Instead of Stones."
  - "Mr. Churchill, the New Liberalism and Relations with Liberal Leaders,", 1954 June 30 (Folder 7: 6)
  - "Training for What?," speech at Founders Day Luncheon for Women's Group in Dhahran, 1955 February 24 (Folder 7: 7)
  - "Doing What Comes Naturally--and Losing Friends,", 1955 May 7 (Folder 7: 8)
  - "What Doth the Lord Require of Thee,", 1955 October 6 (Folder 7: 9)
  - "U.S. History and Middle East Revolutions,", 1957 January 20 (Folder 7: 10)
    Drafts.
  - "On Being an Uncommon Person,", 1957 July 28 (Folder 7: 11)
  - "Educational Developments in the Kingdom 1377-1381 (1957/58-1961/62),", 1962 September 1 (Folder 7: 12)
  - Junior high school commencement address, Saudi Arabia, 1963 July (Folder 7: 13)
  - Sermon at Mead Memorial Chapel, Middlebury College, 1968 January 21 (Folder 7: 14)
  - "The Plague,", 1968 January 21 (Folder 7: 15)
  - "Strive for Excellence,", 1972 June-July (Folder 7: 16)
  - "The Arabs, the Jews, and the Energy Crisis,", 1973 December-1974 February (Folder 7: 17)
  - "Recent Developments in Saudi Arabia: An Attempt to Understand the Arabs,", 1975 March 24 (Folder 7: 18)
  - "The Middle East Conflict,", 1976 April 8 (Folder 7: 19)
    Includes draft and related correspondence.
  - "Saudi Arabia's Emerging Role in World Affairs,", 1976 April 20 (Folder 7: 20)
  - "The Middle East Controversy--Religion, Politics, Oil,", 1977 January 6 (Folder 7: 21)
  - "The Tides of History,", 1978 October 15 (Folder 7: 22)
  - "Iran and Her Neighbors,", 1979 December 4 (Folder 7: 23)
  - Notecards from talks on the Middle East, 1980-1982 and undated (Folder 7: 24-25)
  - "The Persian Gulf States: American Policies and Problems,", 1981 March 2 (Folder 7: 26)
  - "Educational Developments During the Reign of H.M. King Saud Ibn 'Abd Al-Aziz 1953-1964,", 1982 May 6 (Folder 7: 27)
  - "Diary of a Frustrated American,", 1983 February 18 (Folder 7: 28)
    Speech delivered at World Affairs Conference.
  - "The Middle East and U.S. Foreign Policy,", 1986 March 14 (Folder 7: 29)
    Includes drafts.
  - Reactions to speeches and writings, 1963, 1974 (Folder 7: 30)
- Career File, 1928-1965 (Boxes 8-13)
  Consists of reports, newsletters, correspondence, memoranda, speeches, writings, charts, photographs, and printed matter, arranged in five groups based on Snyder's early careers: Professor of Commerce, American University of Beirut; Editor, McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc.; Director, American Friends of the Arabs; Associate Director, Near East College Association; and Military Service and Saudi Arabian Training Mission. Each group is arranged alphabetically by physical form, then chronologically.
  - Professor of Commerce, American University of Beirut, 1928-1929 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1928-1929 (Folder 8: 1)
    - Final examinations, 1928 (Folder 8: 2)
    - Letters received from students and student work, 1928-1929 (Folder 8: 3)
    - Yearbook, 1928 (Folder 8: 4)
  - Editor, McGraw-Hill Publishing Company, Inc., 1929-1943 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1929-1943 (Folder 8: 5)
      Includes some correspondence as president of Near East College Associates.
    - Newsletters, 1931-1942 (Folder 8: 6)
    - Travel schedules, 1931-1934 (Folder 8: 7)
  - Director, American Friends of the Arabs, 1937-1941 (Boxes 8-10)
    - Clippings, 1937-1939 (Folder 8: 8)
    - Correspondence, 1937-1941 (Boxes 8-10)
      - General, A-Y, 1937-1939 (Folder 8: 9-11)
      - Adamic, Louis, 1939 (Folder 8: 12)
      - Anderson, Paul Russell, 1937 (Folder 8: 13)
      - Arab National League, 1937-1938 (Folder 8: 14)
      - Berle, A. A., 1937 (Folder 8: 15)
      - Bliss, Daniel, 1939 (Folder 8: 16)
        Includes an issue of The Christian Century.
      - Burrows, Millar, 1937 (Folder 8: 17)
      - Cavert, Samuel McCrea, 1938 (Folder 8: 18)
      - Davis, Merle L., 1937 (Folder 8: 19)
      - Dorizas, Michail M., 1937 (Folder 8: 20)
      - Duryea, Florence Spencer, 1937-1939 (Folder 8: 21)
      - Eadeh, Najib B., 1938-1939 (Folder 8: 22)
      - Eddy, William Alfred, 1937-1938 (Folder 8: 23)
      - Fisher, Edgar J., 1938 (Folder 8: 24)
      - Flory, Paul and Vera, 1937-1938 (Folder 8: 25)
      - Foreign Policy Association, 1937-1939 (Folder 9: 1)
      - Fosdick, Harry Emerson, 1937-1938 (Folder 9: 2)
      - Grant, Elihu, 1937-1942 (Folder 9: 3-6)
        Includes correspondence of Elihu Grant with others.
      - Hocking, William E., 1937-1938 (Folder 9: 7)
      - Hoskins, Halford L., 1937-1939 (Folder 9: 8)
      - Institute of International Education, 1937 (Folder 9: 9)
      - Jenckes, Virginia E., 1937 (Folder 9: 10)
      - Karpf, M. J., 1937-1938 (Folder 9: 11)
      - Katibah, H. I., 1937-1938 (Folder 9: 12)
      - The League for the American Hospital in Palestine, 1938 (Folder 9: 13)
      - Lindsay, Ronald, 1938 (Folder 9: 14)
      - MacDonald, Malcolm, 1939 (Folder 9: 15)
      - Matthews, Charles D., 1938 (Folder 9: 16)
      - McCown, C. C., 1937-1938 (Folder 9: 17)
      - National Broadcasting Company (Philip Carlin), 1937-1938 (Folder 9: 18)
      - Near East Foundation, 1938 (Folder 9: 19)
      - The New York Times (Arthur H. Sulzberger), 1938-1941 (Folder 9: 20)
      - Penrose, Stephen B. L., 1937 (Folder 9: 21)
      - Pickett, Clarence E. (American Friends Service Committee), 1937 (Folder 9: 22)
      - Rogers, N. W., 1937 (Folder 9: 23)
      - Sarton, George, 1938 (Folder 9: 24)
      - Shatara, F. I., 1937-1939 (Folder 9: 25)
      - Smith, Waldo E., 1937 (Folder 9: 26)
      - Stotz, Carl L., 1937 (Folder 9: 27)
      - Thomas, Elbert D., 1939 (Folder 9: 28)
      - Time (Thomas Krug), 1938 (Folder 9: 29)
      - Torrey, Charles C., 1937 (Folder 9: 30)
      - Turner, Edward L., 1937 (Folder 9: 31)
      - Wagner, Robert F., 1938 (Folder 9: 32)
      - Wriston, Henry Merritt, 1938 (Folder 9: 33)
    - Letters to prospective members, 1937-1938 (Folder 9: 34)
    - Mailing lists and list of invitees, 1937 (Folder 9: 35)
    - Membership acceptance forms, 1938-1939 (Folder 10: 1-2)
    - Newsletters, drafts, 1937-1938 (Folder 10: 3)
    - Notes, circa 1937 (Folder 10: 4)
    - Petitions to President Roosevelt regarding Palestine, 1937 (Folder 10 :5)
    - Printed matter relating to Palestine, 1925-1939 (Box-folder 10: 6-12)
      - Undated (Folder 10: 6)
      - 1925 (Folder 10: 7)
      - 1935-1939 (Folder 10: 8-12)
    - Miscellany, 1937 (Folder 10: 13)
  - Associate Director, Near East College Association, 1928-1947 (Boxes 10-11)
    - Agendas, 1947 (Folder 10: 14)
    - Clippings, 1941-1947 (Folder 10: 15)
    - Correspondence, 1936-1947 (Folder 10: 16-17)
    - Memoranda, 1946 (Folder 11: 1)
    - Menus, 1938 (Folder 11: 2)
    - Names of staff and trustees of Near East colleges, undated (Folder 11: 3)
    - Newsletters, 1945-1947, undated (Folder 11: 4)
    - Policy statement, draft, 1946 (Folder 11: 5)
    - Printed matter from schools in the Near East, 1928-1948 (Folder 11: 6)
    - Programs, 1936-1947 (Folder 11: 7)
    - Reports, 1947 (Folder 11: 8)
    - Salaries and budget, 1947 (Folder 11: 9)
    - Schedules, 1946-1947 (Folder 11: 10)
    - Writings by Bayard Dodge and Homer Davis, 1943-1947 (Folder 11: 11)
    - Miscellany, undated (Folder 11: 12)
  - Military Service and Saudi Arabian Training Mission, 1932-1965 (Boxes 11-13)
    - General military service records, 1932-1965 (Boxes 11-12)
      Includes orders, memoranda, reports, certificates, and other transactions from Snyder's service with the United States Air Force Reserves and relating to military activities in Africa and the Middle East.
      - Undated (Folder 11: 13)
      - 1932-1936 (Folder 11: 14)
      - 1941-1946 (Folder 11: 15-21)
      - 1947-1949 (Folder 12: 1-5)
      - 1952-1958 (Folder 12: 6-11)
      - 1960-1965 (Folder 12: 12)
      - Qualification records and certificates of service, 1942-1949 (Folder 12: 13)
    - Ta'if, 1945 (Box 12)
      - Notebooks with diary entries relating to negotiations for airfield, 1945 (Folder 12: 14)
      - Photographs from training mission, 1945 (Folder 12: 15)
    - Dhahran airfield, 1941-1955, undated (Boxes 12-13)
      - General, 1942-1947, undated (Folder 12: 16)
      - Charts depicting chains of command, 1940s (Folder 12: 17)
      - Construction records, 1948 (Folder 12: 18)
      - Correspondence and memoranda, 1941-1944 (Folder 12: 19)
      - Correspondence and memoranda, 1945-1949 (Folder 13: 1-5)
      - Graduation commencement materials, 1948-1955 (Folder 13: 6)
      - Map, 1942 (Folder 13: 7)
      - Notes, undated (Folder 13: 8)
      - Photographs, 1946-1948 (Folder 13: 9-11)
        - Airplane given to King Saud by President Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1946 (Folder 13: 9)
          Includes expense report for HRS.
        - Buildings and planes at Dhahran airfield, 1947-1948 (Folder 13: 10)
        - Graduation of Saudi Arabian Training Mission class, 1948 July (Folder 13: 11)
      - Reference guide to supply, 1948 (Folder 13: 12)
      - Reports, 1943-1949 (Folder 13: 13)
      - Research on flight schools, undated (Folder 13: 14)
      - Rosters, 1947-1948 (Folder 13: 15)
      - Staff requirements and expenses, circa 1946 (Folder 13: 16)
      - Miscellany, 1944-1948 (Folder 13: 17)
    - Correspondence and writings of Francis A. Kettaneh relating to Palestine and Zionism, 1942-1944 (Folder 13: 18-22)
- Arabian American Oil Company, Education and Arab Training File, 1941-1998 (Boxes 14-24)
  Consists of reports, memoranda, correspondence, newspapers, magazines, charts, notes, writings, yearbooks, and photographs, arranged by department or project, then alphabetically by physical form. Materials relating to the College of Petroleum and Minerals are filed at the end of the series.
  - General, 1941-1998 (Boxes 14-15)
    - Chronologies, 1959 (Folder 14: 1)
    - Employment solicitation letter from Aramco to Snyder, 1948 (Folder 14: 2)
    - Lists of textbooks, 1957-1963 (Folder 14: 3)
    - Memoranda, 1947-1962 (Folder 14: 4)
    - Performance review guide, 1959 (Folder 14: 5)
    - Printed materials, 1948-1998 (Folder 14: 6-8)
    - Reports, 1941-1969, undated (Folder 14-15)
      - Undated (Folder 14: 9)
      - 1941-1951 (Folder 14: 10)
      - 1955-1956 (Folder 14: 11-12)
      - 1957-1960 (Folder 15: 1-4)
      - 1963-1969 (Folder 15: 5-10)
    - Telephone directory, 1969 (Folder 15: 11)
  - Training Department (Dhahran), 1943-1966 (Boxes 15-20)
    - General, 1953-1964 (Folder 15: 12)
    - Conference materials, 1949-1953 (Folder 15: 13)
    - Functional operating plans, 1957-1966 (Folder 16: 1)
    - Manuals and workbooks, 1943-1969 (Folder 16: 2-10)
      - Undated (Folder 16: 2)
      - 1943 (Folder 16: 3)
      - 1949-1953 (Folder 16: 4-6)
      - 1959 (Folder 16: 7)
      - 1962-1965 (Folder 16: 8-9)
      - 1969 (Folder 16: 10)
    - Memoranda, 1958-1965 (Folder 16: 11)
    - Personal correspondence file of HRS, 1950-1963 (Boxes 16-17)
      - 1950-1957 (Folder 16: 12-15)
      - 1958-1968 (Folder 17: 1-7)
    - Policies, 1950-1965 (Folder 17: 8-9)
    - Presentation to the Executive Management Council, 1961 (Folder 17: 10)
    - Projects and programs, 1949-1965 (Boxes 18-19)
      - Dhahran district training program outlines and related materials, 1949-1951 (Folder 18: 1)
      - Out of kingdom training, 1963-1964 (Folder 18: 2)
      - Saudi Arab utilization, 1951 (Folder 18: 3)
      - Saudi vestibule training, 1951 (Folder 18: 4)
      - Scholarships, 1954-1965 (Folder 18: 5)
      - Sidon Center supervisory training, 1951 (Folder 18: 6-13)
      - Vocational school project, 1954-1955 (Folder 18: 14)
      - Vocational school project, 1957-1958 (Folder 19: 1)
    - Reports, 1949-1966 (Boxes 19-20)
      - 1949-1957 (Folder 19: 2-12)
      - 1959 (Folder 20: 1)
      - 1962 (Folder 20: 2)
      - 1965-1966 (Folder 20: 3)
    - Statistics, 1955-1960 (Folder 20: 4)
    - Writings on Aramco training model and education of Saudi Arabian workforce, by author, 1952-1959 (Box 20)
      - Hall, Robert King, 1952-1959 (Folder 20: 5)
      - Lebkicher, Roy, 1951-1957 (Folder 20: 6-7)
      - Spence, Ralph, 1956 (Folder 20: 8)
      - Weidner, C. Ken, 1952-1959 (Folder 20: 9)
  - Near East College Association and Aramco education survey, 1946-1947 (Boxes 20-21)
    - Chronology of events, 1947 (Folder 20: 10)
    - Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Folder 20: 11)
    - Reports, drafts and final, 1947 (Folder 20: 12-13)
    - Research materials, 1947 (Folder 20: 14)
    - Photographs, 1947 (Folder 21: 1)
  - Schools, 1953-1978 (Box 21)
    Includes records of Saudi Arabian Government/Aramco built schools.
    - General, 1953-1965 (Folder 21: 3)
    - Curricula, 1958-1966 (Folder 21: 4)
      See also: Oversize Materials.
    - Drafts of letters to Howard Page regarding company-built schools, 1964-1965 (Folder 21: 5)
    - Enrollment, 1953-1978 (Folder 21: 6)
    - Expenditures, 1961 (Folder 21: 7)
    - Reports and working papers regarding schools for girls, 1959-1964 (Folder 21: 8)
    - Statistics issued by Ministry of Finance and National Economy, 1972-1974 (Folder 21: 9)
  - Saudi Arabia Government-Ministry of Education, 1958-1961 (Box 21)
    - Meetings and translations of reports on public and industrial education, 1961-1965 (Folder 21: 10-12)
    - Monograph, 1958 (Folder 21: 13)
      In Arabic.
  - Government Relations Department-Arabian Research Division reports and press summaries, 1955-1965 (Folder 22: 1-3)
  - Yearbooks from senior staff schools in Dhahran, 1953-1955 (Folder 22: 4-6)
  - College of Petroleum and Minerals, 1950-1987 (Boxes 22-24)
    - Announcements to faculty and students, 1966-1972 (Folder 22: 7)
    - Agreement for construction of vocational secondary school, 1961, undated (Box-folder 22: 8)
    - Estimates of costs and expenditures, circa 1965-1967 (Box-folder 22: 9)
    - Photographs of scale model, circa 1965 (Box-folder 22: 10)
    - Architectural plans, 1965 (Folder 22: 11-13)
    - Architectural plans and related materials, 1965-1973 (Folder 23: 1-5)
    - Background information on college, 1965 (Folder 23: 6)
    - Brochures, 1965-1971, undated (Folder 23: 7)
    - Candidate files for the position of Assistant Dean for Academic Affairs, 1965-1966 (Folder 23: 8)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1987 (Folder 23: 9)
    - Course materials and schedules, 1966-1968 (Folder 23: 10-12)
    - Daily reports, 1965-1966 (Folder 23: 13)
    - Directories, 1966-1971 (Folder 24: 1)